HUSSEIN ALMAWLA

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER



+961 71321357



info@hmawla.com



mawla.com

WORK PORTFOLIO

github.com/hmawla

linkedin.com/in/hmawla

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

PHP, Java, Dart, JavaScript, Swift, C, C++.

PROGRAMMING FRAMEWORKS

Laravel. Vue.JS. Micronaut, Flutter, Symfony, jQuery, .NET, Angular, React Native.

SKILLS

FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPMENT

VERY HIGH

NATIVE PROGRAM DEVELOPMENT

VERY HIGH

MOBILE DEVELOPMENT

VERY HIGH

PROJECT MANAGEMENT

HIGH

UI DESIGN

HIGH

NETWORKING

MEDIUM

PROFILE

Experienced Information Technology Specialist with a demonstrated history of working in the telecommunications industry. Skilled in Web and Program Development, Project Management, Networking, UI Designing and Development. Strong information technology professional. Ranked first across Lebanon in TS Management Information System (MIS) 2018.

EDUCATION

HUSSEIN MAKTABE HIGHSCHOOL

2010 - 2013

LEBANESE UNIVERSITY

2013 - 2015

AL-AFAK INSTITUTE

2016 - 2018

MATN UNIVERSITY COLLEGE

2018 - 2020

WORK EXPERIENCE

COMPU 2000

MAINTENANCE MANAGER\ 2013 - 2015

MAWLA TELECOM L.L.C.

HEAD OF MARKETING & IT DEPARTMENT \ 2015 - 2019

AL-AFAK INSTITUTE

COMPUTER & PROGRAMMING INSTRUCTOR 2018 - PRESENT

MTS L.L.C.

CORE DEVELOPMENT DIRECTOR\ 2018 - 2020

FREELANCE FULL STACK DEVELOPER

2019 – PRESENT

VOICELINX SOLUTIONS

MOBILE DEVELOPER\ 2019 - PRESENT

UNTITLED DEVELOPERS

FOUNDER\ 2020 - PRESENT

MAIN PROJECTS



Pocket Cards

- Type: Mobile ApplicationRole: Director & Developer
- **Description:** Gift cards vouchers selling application
- Year of development: 2017



Class App

- Type: Mobile ApplicationRole: Director & Developer
- Description: E-Commerce application
- Year of development: 2020



WaynYo

- Type: Mobile Application
 Role: Mobile Developer
 Description: Social Platform
- Year of development: 2019



Mawla Telecom Products

- Type: Website & Mobile Application
- Role: Director & Developer
- **Description:** E-Commerce & Portfolio
- Year of development: 2015



MTS Lebanon

- Type: Website
- Role: Director & Developer
- **Description:** E-Commerce website
- Year of development: 2018



Atelier-Mag

- Type: Website
- Role: Director & Developer
- Description: Art Gallery websiteYear of development: 2020

Chordz E-Comm

Type: Website

Role: Director & Developer

• **Description:** E-Commerce website

• Year of development: 2020

CoPrev

Type: WebsiteRole: Developer

Description: Medical diagnosis application

that targets COVID-19 spread **Year of development:** 2020

OTHERS

- 1. Maintaining and collaborating to Arts'N'Code Open-Source Library (GitHub)
- 2. Collaborating to Android Framework
- 3. Collaborating to Flutter Framework
- 4. Collaborating to Laravel Framework
- 5. Including many other internal business management projects for MTS L.L.C

DEGREES

- 1. General Sciences (GS) Secondary Degree
- 2. Senior Technician **(TS)** in Management & Information Systems **(MIS)**. Ranked First Across Lebanon (2018)
- 3. Bachelor in Computer Sciences. GPA: 3.8/4

Achieved projects and licenses can be found on LinkedIn and GitHub

THANK YOU FOR READING



REFERENCES

- 1. https://hmawla.com
- 2. https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=app.pocketcards.android
- 3. https://play.google.com/store/apps/developer?id=Untitled+Developers
- 4. http://waynyo.com/
- 5. https://mawlatelecom.com
- 6. https://mts-Lebanon.com
- 7. https://classcellulars.com
- 8. https://atelier-mag.com
- 9. https://chordz.net
- 10. https://github.com/Arts-n-Code
- 11. https://github.com/hmawla
- 12. https://linkedin.com/in/hmawla